Guide to the Tamiment Library Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Collection TAM.507
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Collection
2007-present
TAM.507
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
246.0 websites and 2.2 TB
The Tamiment Library Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Collection was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. The collection contains periodically archived websites of New York City metropolitan area Labor Unions, especially those whose records are held by the Tamiment Library's Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives (designated by the New York City Central Labor Council as the official repository for their member unions' records), websites of selected national labor unions, and websites of labor movement related organizations, e.g. organizations that support the goals/activity of organized labor and social and economic justice for working people, and websites that promote democracy within labor unions. Web archiving is an evolving practice, please be patient if sites do not display accurately.
Tamiment Library.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Websites are directly captured from the website's respective source.
Scope and Contents note
The Tamiment Library Labor Unions and Organizations Web Collection, first began in 2007, contains websites of local New York and national labor unions, especially those whose records are held by the Tamiment Library's Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives (designated by the New York City Central Labor Council as the official repository for their member unions' records). The collection also contains websites of labor movement related organizations, e.g. organizations that support the goals/activity of organized labor and social and economic justice for working people; and websites that promote democracy within labor unions. Some of these organizations are multi-issue organizations, besides labor activism, some organizations work for women's rights, environmental causes, and labor history and education. These websites contain a huge variety of media, which include YouTube videos, pdfs, blog postings (including Tumblr and Wordpress blogs), petitions, news feeds, audio, and other media. These websites often act to document and update upon the organizations’ activities, schedule upcoming events, build awareness of their causes, or other media. Most websites are captured quarterly, but during periods of rapid update, the website are captured weekly or monthly. The links in the container list take the user to the main Web Archiving Service (WAS) page for each website, which contain more detailed description of each website.
The web collection documents the publicly available content of the web page, it does not archive material that is password protected or blocked due to robot txt exclusions. Although attempts are made to completely archive the entirety of a website, linked pages are often not captured, as can be pages within the host URL.
The types of materials in the web collection--publications, news listings, leaflets, and other materials that publicize events and activities--were formerly collected in analog form by Tamiment librarians and archivists are increasingly being published online. Therefore, it is important to capture these websites to document the activities of these unions and organizations.
Historical/Biographical Note
Tamiment Library, New York University, a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action, began web archiving in 2007 as part of a grant given by the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program (NDIPP) of the Library of Congress, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. As most unions, left movements, progressive organizations, and others stop creating ephemeral material and paper based collections and move most of their administrative and informational material to the web, Tamiment felt the need to continue to document the changing face of the labor and left movement into the web era. Tamiment uses the California Digital Library’s Web Archiving Service (WAS) as their tool to capture and preserve websites. WAS was created in 2007 and Tamiment is one of its earliest partners. The California Digital Library hosts the storage and infrastructure to the project. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Our other web collections include:
Alternative Mass Media and News (TAM 503)
Anarchism (TAM 504)
Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism (TAM 505)
Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp (TAM 506)
Other Left Activism (TAM 508)
Jewish American Left (TAM 511)
Prisoner Rights (TAM 512)
Arts and the Cultural Left (TAM 540)
Peace Movements (TAM 541)
Feminism and Women's Movements (TAM 566)
Economic and Social Justice (TAM 599)
Education and Student Movements (TAM 600)
Civil Rights and Human Rights (TAM 601)
Housing (TAM 606)
Animal Rights (TAM 617)
Electoral Politics and Parties (TAM 618)
Environmentalism and Green Movements (TAM 619)
These can be found here.
The Printed Ephermera Collection on Trade Unions (PE 001) also contains related analog materials related to some of the unions found in this collection.
Arrangement
Websites arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions. Archived websites are made publically available 6 months after initial capture. Access to the websites can be found by clicking directly on the links in the container list or visiting the public page.
Take Down Policy
Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor the website owner’s request to remove their website from the collection.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. This can include missing video or image files, the website could display as an index, or a number of different display issues. Tamiment's web archives are stored on an external service and can be slow to load, please be patient. Searching capabilities are available on the archives main page, which can be found here.
AFL-CIO. New York City Central Labor Council.; Labor movement |z United States.; Labor union democracy |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor union democracy |z United States.; Labor unions |z New York (State); Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Working class |z United States
- Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.), 2007-present
  - 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East, Jun 2010-present
    Scope and Content Note
    United Healthcare Workers East (1199SEIU), founded in 1932 as the Local 1199, is a local union of the Service Employees International Union, representing more than 300,000 members. Members work in homecare, hospital and nursing home industries, as well as pharmacies, freestanding clinics, and other healthcare settings. The mission of the union is to improve and expand quality patient care, to protect and improve the lives of members and their families, and to work in solidarity with working people in SEIU’s communities and around the world. In 1998, they affiliated to the Service Employees International Union (SEIU). Since 1998, 15 healthcare local unions throughout New York State, New Jersey, the District of Columbia, Florida, Maryland and Massachusetts have merged with 1199SEIU.
  - Actors' Equity Association, Sep 2007-present
    Actors' Equity Association ("AEA" or "Equity"), founded in 1913, is the labor union that represents more than 48,000 actors and stage managers in the United States. Equity seeks to advance, promote and foster the art of live theatre as an essential component of our society. Equity negotiates wages and working conditions and provides a wide range of benefits, including health and pension plans, for its members. Actors' Equity is a member of the AFL-CIO, and is affiliated with FIA, an international organization of performing arts unions.
  - Actors' Fund of America, Sep 2007-present
    The Actors Fund, a nonprofit human services organization founded in 1882, serves professionals in film, theater, television, music, opera, and dance through programs that address their professional needs. The Fund serves more than 12,000 performing arts and entertainment professionals across the country every year, and reaches hundreds of thousand through the Fund’s online resources. The Fund operates as a safety net, to provide programs and services, including comprehensive social services, health services, supportive and affordable housing, employment and training services, and skilled nursing and assisted living care for performing arts and entertainment professionals in need.
  - AFL-CIO New York City Central Labor Council, Sep 2007-present
    The New York City Central Labor Council (NYCCLC) is a non-profit labor membership organization devoted to supporting, advancing and advocating for the working people of New York City. The NYCCLC brings together 300 local unions from every trade, occupation, public and private sector of the New York economy. The Council represents 1.3 million workers, including teachers, truck drivers, operating engineers, nurses, construction workers, electricians, firefighters, retail workers, janitors, train operators, bakers, and others. NYCCLC is affiliated with the AFL-CIO.
  - AFL-CIO Working Families Vote 2008, Aug 2009-Mar 2010
    AFL-CIO Working Families Vote 2008 was an online political action arm of the AFL-CIO for the U.S. 2008 elections.
  - AFL-CIO.org, Dec 2009-present
    The American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO) is a voluntary federation of 56 national and international labor unions. The AFL-CIO was created in 1955 by the merger of the AFL and the CIO. The AFL-CIO union movement represents 12.2 million members, including teachers, miners, firefighters, farm workers, bakers, engineers, pilots, public employees, doctors, nurses, painters, plumbers and other workers.
  - Air Line Pilots Association (ALPA), Dec 2009-present
    The Air Line Pilots Association, International (ALPA) is the largest airline pilot union in the world and represents nearly 53,000 pilots at 36 U.S. and Canadian airlines. Founded in 1931, the Association is chartered by the AFL-CIO and the Canadian Labour Congress. Known internationally as US-ALPA, it is a member of the International Federation of Air Line Pilot Associations.
  - Albert Shanker Institute, Jul 2009-present
    The Albert Shanker Institute is a nonprofit foundation dedicated to advancing democratic ideals, improving the quality of public education, and conducting research in the labor movement and the sociology of work. The foundation sponsors research, holds roundtable discussions, and publishes various reports. The Institute was named for Albert Shanker (1928-1997), the late president of the American Federation of Teachers.
  - Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU), Dec 2009-present
    The Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU) is the largest labor organization representing transit workers in the United States and Canada. Founded in 1892, the ATU today is comprised of over 190,000 members in 264 local unions spread across 44 states and nine provinces. Composed of metropolitan, interstate, and school bus drivers; paratransit, light rail, subway, streetcar, and ferry boat operators; mechanics and other maintenance workers; clerks, baggage handlers, municipal employees, and others. The ATU works to promote transit issues and fights for the interests of its hard-working members. ATU is a member the AFL-CIO, and the Canadian Labor Congress (CLC).
  - Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181, Jan 2013-present
    Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181 is the largest local in the United States for the Amalgamated Transit Union. It represents drivers, escorts, school bus drivers, and mechanics in New York City, Westchester County and Long Island. The website contains information on their school bus strike in 2013, their pension and welfare fund, and a calendar.
  - American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE), Dec 2009-present
    The American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE), founded in 1932, is an American labor union representing over 600,000 employees of the federal government, about 5,000 employees of the District of Columbia, and a few hundred private sector employees, mostly in and around federal facilities. Workers in many functions of government at every federal agency depend upon AFGE for legal representation, legislative advocacy, technical expertise and informational services. It is affiliated with the AFL-CIO.
  - American Federation of Musicians, Local 802, Sep 2007-present
    Local 802 of the American Federation of Musicians is a local union of professional musicians living or working in New York City, Nassau and Suffolk counties, New York. The union's mission is to fight for the interests and well being of the musicians employed in New York's music and entertainment industries through organizing and collective bargaining as well as through legislative and political action.
  - American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada (AFM), Dec 2009-present
    The American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada (AFM) is a labor union of professional musicians in the United States and Canada, founded in 1896. The AFM represents the interests of professional musicians by negotiating fair agreements, protecting ownership of recorded music, securing benefits such as health care and pension, and lobbying legislators.
  - American Federation of School Administrators (AFSA), Dec 2009-present
    The American Federation of School Administrators (AFSA) is the national education union for school administrators, which provides labor relations and professional and occupational services to public school principals, vice principals, administrators and supervisors in diverse school districts across the U.S., Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands. Affiliated with the AFL-CIO, AFSA has been working for quality public school education for students of all backgrounds since 1976. AFSA’s mission is to promote the professional, occupational, and economic interests of its 20,000 members and work for the highest quality public school education for all pupils.
  - American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), Dec 2009-present
    American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), founded in 1932, is a public services employees union with more than 1.6 million active and retired members, consisting primarily of workers in the local and state government and in the health care industry. AFSCME organizes for social and economic rights of their members in the workplace and through political action and legislative advocacy.
  - American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.), Sep 2007-present
    District Council 37 (DC 37) is a local union of the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) which represents New York City public employees and employees in the healthcare industry. DC 37 was founded in 1944.
  - American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) Local 1930 (New York, N.Y.), Sep 2007-present
    The New York Public Library Guild Local 1930, formed in 1968, represents almost 2,000 clericals, library technical assistants, information assistants, librarians, and other titles. Members of Local 1930 are employed by the New York Public Library, by the City of New York in its branch libraries, and the libraries of mayoral departments and agencies. The bargaining unit includes professional, non-professional and technical positions. As an activist union, they believe libraries are the backbone of democracy and unions are the vehicles to defend the economic rights of clerks, library technical assistants, information assistants, librarians, and others.
  - American Federation of Teachers (AFT), Dec 2009-present
    The American Federation of Teachers (AFT), founded in 1916, represents the economic, social and professional interests of classroom teachers. It is an affiliated international union of the AFL-CIO. The AFT has more than 3,000 local affiliates nationwide, 43 state affiliates, and more than 1.5 million members. Five divisions within the organization represent the broad spectrum of AFT's membership: teachers; paraprofessionals and school-related personnel (PSRP); local, state and federal employees; higher education faculty and staff; and nurses and other healthcare professionals. In addition, the union includes more than 170,000 retiree members.
  - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, Sep 2007-Jul 2012
    The American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA), founded in 1937, is a national labor union representing performers, journalists and other artists working in the entertainment and news media. AFTRA's scope of representation covers broadcast, public and cable television, radio, sound recordings, “non-broadcast” and industrial material, as well as Internet and digital programming. AFTRA advocates on legislative and public policy issues that directly affect members’ wages and working conditions. This includes lobbying and support for such issues as ownership consolidation in the broadcast industry, Equal Employment Opportunity laws and regulations, copyright and performance rights issues, “non-compete” restrictions, OSHA and local safety regulations, and more. AFTRA also represents artists and journalists in judicial proceedings, often as amicus, and before the U.S. Copyright Office. In 2012, AFTRA merged with the Screen Actors Guild (SAG) to form SAGAFTRA.
  - American Guild of Musical Artists, Nov 2008-present
    The American Guild of Musical Artists, AFL-CIO (AGMA), founded in 1936, is an American labor union that represents 8,000 current and retired opera singers, ballet and other dancers, opera directors, backstage production personnel at opera and dance companies, and figure skaters. AGMA is a branch of Associated Actors and Artistes of America.
  - American Guild of Variety Artists, Apr 2012-present
    The American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA) is an AFL-CIO-affiliated labor union founded in 1939 to represent performing artists and stage managers for live performances in the variety field. The variety area of performance includes singers and dancers in touring shows and in theatrical revues, theme park performers, skaters, circus performers, comedians & stand-up comics, cabaret & club artists, lecturers, poets, monologists, spokespersons, and variety performers working at private parties special events. AGVA is a branch of The Associated Actors and Artistes of America. AGVA negotiates contracts and provides relief for members. The website contains information on their relief funds, auditions, news, and other information.
  - American Labor Studies Center (ALSC), Mar 2012-present
    The American Labor Studies Center is a nonprofit organization whose mission is to collect, analyze, evaluate, create and disseminate labor history and labor studies curricula and related materials, aligned to the various state and national standards, to kindergarten through 12th grade teachers nationwide. They will include such areas as the history, organization, activities, and issues affecting the labor movement and the political, economic, and cultural aspects of workers and their unions. The ALSC sponsors workshops, courses, conferences and other events to acquaint teachers with the curriculum and related materials. The ALSC is located in Troy, New York in the Kate Mullany house. The website contains information for teachers, students, and unions.
  - American Postal Workers Union (APWU), Dec 2009-present
    The American Postal Workers Union (APWU), formed in 1971, represents more than 220,000 United States Postal Service employees and retirees, and nearly 2,000 private-sector mail workers. It represents employees of the United States Postal Service who are clerks, maintenance employees, and motor vehicle service workers. APWU works for decent pay, benefits, and safe working conditions for workers they represent. The APWU is a Union Network International and AFL-CIO affiliate.
  - American Rights at Work, Sep 2007-present
    American Rights at Work (ARAW), founded in 2003, is a U.S. nonpartisan, nonprofit organization that advocates for workers and their right to form unions without interference. ARAW is a labor policy and advocacy organization dedicated to educating the American public about the many barriers that workers face when they attempt to exercise their rights to organize and engage in collective bargaining. The organization conducts research into United States labor law and the National Labor Relations Board as they relate to unions, employer actions in union organizing, and collective bargaining campaign. ARAW’s resources include publications, Workers’ Rights Clearinghouse database, and Workers’ Rights Watch: Eye on the National Labor Relations Board.
  - American Social History Project, Jul 2012-present
    The American Social History Project/Center for Media and Learning (ASHP/CML), founded in 1981, produces print, visual, and multimedia materials that explore the social and cultural history of the United States. They also lead development seminars. The website contains their digital projects, their “Who Built America?” series, documentaries, teaching services, and a their new media lab blog.
  - Association for Union Democracy, Sep 2007-present
    The Association for Union Democracy (AUD) is a pro-labor, non-profit organization dedicated solely to advancing the principles and practices of democratic trade unionism in the North American labor movement. AUD provides organizing, educational, and legal assistance to those working for greater membership control of their unions. AUD has operated several projects including, the Union Democracy Worker Education Project; the Women's Project; the Workers Rights Clinic; the AUD Steelworkers Fair Election Project; and the Longshore Workers Democracy Project.
  - Association of Flight Attendants (AFA-CWA), Dec 2009-present
    The Association of Flight Attendants-CWA (AFA-CWA), founded in 1945, is a union representing flight attendants in the United States. In 2011, AFA represents nearly 60,000 Flight Attendants at 23 airlines, making it the world's largest Flight Attendant union. The goal of flight attendants who become part of AFA-CWA is to negotiate better pay, benefits, working conditions, work rules at their airline, and to improve their safety on the job. The AFA is part of the Communication Workers of America (CWA), an affiliate with the AFL-CIO, and an affiliate of the 5 million member International Transport Workers' Federation.
  - Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers and Grain Millers International Union (BCTGM), Dec 2009-present